nacha.org 2019-07-01

# Privacy Policy | Nacha

Nacha is committed to safeguarding your privacy. This website adheres to the following policy concerning the privacy of any personally identifiable information that may be collected about you and personally identifiable information about others you provide in connection with your use of certain services provided through this website (“Third Party Information”).

**THIS POLICY ADDRESSES:**

  * Your visit to the nacha.org website,
  * The information that Nacha collects about you and the personal information that you submit to Nacha to access services through this website,
  * How your personal information is collected and used,
  * When your personal information may be shared with third parties,
  * Our use and sharing of Third Party Information submitted by you on the website, and
  * Security of information.

**YOUR WEBSITE VISITS AND INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

You do not need to provide any personal information to visit public sections of this website. To evaluate this website and improve our service to you, our web servers may automatically collect usage data, such as Internet provider address, browser type and access time.

**COLLECTING INFORMATION ABOUT YOU**

This website will only collect personally identifiable information about you if you voluntarily supply it (e.g., membership and conference registrations, purchasing Nacha’s products, enrollment in Nacha rule-making or other programs, surveys, etc.). Nacha is the administrator of this website. Nacha does not sell or rent information about you from this website. Nacha does provide the contact information for conference attendees to exhibitors and sponsors at Nacha’s conferences; however, conference attendees have the option of opting out of this distribution of their contact information.

**USAGE OF COLLECTED INFORMATION ABOUT YOU**

We use industry standard software to create summary statistics of the website usage data we collect, which may then be used to highlight what our visitors find interesting, to improve the website design specifications, to identify system performance issues and for other internal purposes.

We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer the website. Data gathered from logging your IP address is not tied to your personal information and is not used to identify you.

**COOKIES**

Like most websites, our server may place a “cookie,” or small file, in the browser of a visitor's computer. This cookie will assign a user a unique number that allows this website to save information so that the information does not need to be re-entered and makes it more convenient for you to use the website. At no time will this cookie reveal to others any information about you.

**YOUR INFORMATION**

If you register to access various services on the website, you may be asked to complete online registration forms and submit your personal information such as your name, address, phone number, email address, payment method and personal preference information. You may be asked to confirm enrollment or your identity by entering a User ID and password, clicking on “acceptance buttons,” or other methods to verify your identity. You also may be asked to submit additional personal information about you or financial information in order to use certain specific services.

**HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Providing your personal information not only enables you to access various services offered on the website, but it also enables us to provide you with better service generally. We may use this information to contact you to respond to an inquiry we receive from you or to keep you informed about Nacha and its services. If you choose to communicate with Nacha by email, then email from Nacha to you will be considered to be sent with your consent and will be accessible to anyone who has access to your email.

We may collect email addresses to improve our service to our members and website users. In some cases, we may contact you to let you know about new products or services. If you do not wish to be contacted by us for this purpose, or you believe you are receiving our communications in error or no longer want to receive them, you may inform us by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in any email from Nacha marketing a product or service. We generally will discontinue this type of contact with you within 10 days after we receive your email.

We request that you protect the confidentiality of any User ID and password you use to access any of your services online. You are responsible for all activity on the website accessed by your User ID and password. Access by Nacha’s employees or consultants to any personal information about you is limited to only information necessary to provide the business service offered and to allow employees or consultants to perform their duties for Nacha.

To provide you with services offered on the website, or to complete transactions or requests you initiate on the website, we may transfer you to outside services provided by third-party operators. In certain instances, the third-party content may be “framed” in such a way that it appears that you are still on Nacha’s website. In such cases, we will have agreements with those third parties whose websites you may be transferred to, under which the third parties agree to maintain the confidentiality of your personal information and to use it only to help us serve you or comply with legal requirements.

**SHARING YOUR INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES**

Other than as set forth herein, we will not disclose your personal information to third parties without your written consent (which consent may be obtained electronically, such as by email), unless we reasonably believe the disclosure is essential to the conduct of the company’s business or to provide services to you, including but not limited to where such disclosure is required by law, or if we believe such action is necessary in order to: (1) conform to the requirements of the law or comply with legal process served upon us; (2) protect or defend our legal rights or property, this website, or our users; (3) investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or violations of the terms and conditions for using this website; or (4) resolve customer disputes or inquiries.

We engage other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include processing credit card payments, and delivering packages. They have access to your personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. We do not provide your personal information to third parties for telemarketing, email or direct mail solicitation. When we contract with other companies to market or advertise products for Nacha, we require that those companies also protect your personal information.

**THIRD PARTY INFORMATION SUBMITTED BY YOU**

Under certain sections of this website, you may submit Third Party Information about commercial relationships, including information about third-party natural persons in their capacities as directors, managers, employees, or other representatives of a commercial entity. Information about such natural persons may include their names and contact information. We may use and share with others the Third Party Information you submit, including information about third-party natural persons, to provide the services for which such information was entered, to maintain the security, integrity and quality of the ACH network, to prevent fraud or other unlawful activity, to comply with legal requirements, or as otherwise disclosed in the terms of the specific service.

**LINKS**

While browsing the website, you may encounter hypertext links to other third-party operated websites. These other third-party websites may send their own cookies to you, log your IP address and otherwise collect data or solicit personal information. Nacha DOES NOT CONTROL AND IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR WHAT THIRD PARTIES DO IN CONNECTION WITH THEIR WEBSITES, OR HOW THEY HANDLE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION. PLEASE EXERCISE CAUTION AND CONSULT THE PRIVACY POLICIES POSTED ON EACH THIRD-PARTY WEB SITE FOR FURTHER INFORMATION.

**SECURITY**

Our policies and procedures limit access to your personal information to those with a business reason to know such information. We also limit access to Third Party Information to those who may have a legitimate business purpose for such information.

Nacha employs Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt the transmission of your nonpublic personally identifiable financial and transaction information as well as Third Party Information over the Internet. Nacha also utilizes additional security devices, such as firewalls, security patches and anti-virus programs, to protect your nonpublic personally identifiable information and Third Party Information.

Access to your nonpublic personally identifiable financial information is limited, through password protection devices and physical safeguards, to authorized employees as necessary to perform the requested transaction. We reveal only partial digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. However, we cannot guarantee the confidentiality or security of your browser or any communication transmitted or accessible over the Internet. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer.

Nacha works to maintain the privacy of your personally identifiable information (name, mailing address, email address, etc.) and Third Party Information that may be collected though our website. This website has security measures in place; however, Nacha does not represent, warrant or guarantee that personal information or Third Party Information will be protected against unauthorized access, loss, misuse or alterations. Similarly, Nacha disclaims liability for personal information or Third Party Information submitted through this website. Users are hereby advised that they submit such personal information or Third Party Information at their own risk.

**CHANGES TO POLICY**

Nacha reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Please review the contents of this Privacy Policy frequently, as we may amend it from time to time to reflect changes in our services and our policies relating to data privacy. Amendments will become effective when posted on the website. Nacha will not provide you with a notice of any change in this website policy. It is your responsibility to monitor and review any updates to this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this website, or online services provided by Nacha, after such posting will be deemed your acceptance of these changes to our Privacy Policy.

You may direct questions regarding this policy to: [info@nacha.org](mailto:info@nacha.org).

**EFFECTIVE DATE OF POLICY**

_This policy was revised on December 11, 2017._
